Guide to the Edison Cylinder Collection, 1902-1916 CAM.EDI.1982.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- "The Tales of Hoffmann-Barcarole" (Cylinder EDI 0039)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, American Symphony Orchestra, 3070. There is some very slight pitting of the inner plaster core at the top edge. The cylinder is in its original case.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder7602
- "Kentucky Home" (Cylinder EDI 0040)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as Crescent Trio, 4420. There is some slight mold damage to the inner plaster core at the bottom edge. The cylinder is in the wrong case. The lid reads, "Nearer My God to Thee." The lid is in two pieces.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder8087
- "Tell Mother I'll be There" (Cylinder EDI 0041)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Wheeler and Mixed Quartet, 1533. There is some slight mold damage to the inner plaster core and plastic at the bottom edge. The cylinder is in its original case and includes a leaflet about the song.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder609
- "Swanee" (Cylinder EDI 0042)
  This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type. The performer and ID number are printed as, Al Bernard and Frank M. Kamplain, 3988. The cylinder was not able to be removed from the case. The lid could not be safely removed and so the cylinder could not be inspected. It is unknown if the cylinder is in its original case.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder7771
- "We're Tenting Tonight" (Cylinder EDI 0043)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Knickerbocker Quartet, 1881. There is some slight mold damage to the plastic on the bottom edge in places. The case has no lid and is falling apart.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder0296
- "I'm Sorry I Made You Cry" (Cylinder EDI 0044)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, H. Soman, 3655. The inner plaster core is severely dirty. The case has no lid and no bottom.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
  http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=4&query=i%27m+sorry+I+made+you+cry&num=1&start=2&sortBy=&sortOrder=ia
- "I Might be Your Once-in-a-While Angel Face" (Cylinder EDI 0045)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Leola Lucy and Chorus, 4013. There is some slight pitting to the inner plaster core. There are also some spots or accretions on the plastic in places. The cylinder has no case, only a lid with the correct title on the label.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder6526
- "Coon Song, Abraham Jefferson Washington Lee" (Cylinder EDI 0046)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The ID number is printed as 9423. There is no performer printed on the cylinder. There is severe pitting and loss to the wax playing surface on a large portion of the cylinder. The inner core is severely dirty. The cylinder is unplayable. It is in a case with no lid.
- "Nearer My God to Thee" (Cylinder EDI 0047)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as Knickerbocker Quartet, 1557. There is some very slight browning of the plastic on the top rim. The cylinder is in the wrong case. The case has no lid. The cylinder could not be transferred to the correct case as that case cannot be safely removed from another cylinder.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder641
- "Somebody Cares" (Cylinder EDI 0048)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are listed as, Rodeheaver, 2354. There is some very slight pitting to the bottom edge of the inner plaster core. There are also some slight cracks to the bottom edge of the plastic. The plastic is also lightening around the edges. The cylinder is in its original case.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder155
- "Annie, My Own-Fox Trot" (Cylinder EDI 0049)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, H. Radermann's Jazz Orch., 4217. There is some very slight pitting to the inner plaster core. There are also some moderate dirt accretions to the plastic in places. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=4&query=annie+my+own&num=1&start=1&sortBy=&sortOrder=id
- "Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming" (Cylinder EDI 0050)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Knickerbocker Quartet, 1933. There are some slight cracks and yellowing to the top rim of the plastic. The entire cylinder is lighter blue than normal for unknown reasons. The case has a lid with no label.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder8706
- "Old Black Joe" (Cylinder EDI 0051)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Knickerbocker Quartet, 1865. There is some slight discoloration and mold damage to the cylinder. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder0190
- "Kentucky Home" (Cylinder EDI 0052)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Crescent Trio, 4420. There are some very slight mold accretion spots to the cylinder. The case has a lid with no label.
- "Unknown" (Cylinder EDI 0053)
  This is a black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The ID number is printed as 8781. The cylinder has crumbled into many small pieces inside of the case. The performer and title of the cylinder could not be found on the pieces. The cylinder is unplayable. The case lid reads, "Old Folks at Home."
- "Hard Times Come again No More" (Cylinder EDI 0054)
  This is a black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Quartette, 9120. There is some very slight mold accretion and one pit mark on the wax. The cylinder is in the wrong case. The lid reads, "Bullfinches, Clarinet."
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder2874
- "Old Folks at Home With Variations" (Piano) (Cylinder EDI 0055)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Benoist, 1908. There are some very slight cracks to the inner plaster core at the bottom of the cylinder. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and maybe downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder811
- "Swanee" (Cylinder EDI 0056)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Al Bernard & I Kamplain, 3988. There is some slight mold damage and moderate pitting to the inner plaster core. The cylinder is in the wrong case. The lid is mostly illegible except for the ID number which reads, "3375."
- "I Love the Land of Old Black Joe" (Cylinder EDI 0057)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Vaughn de Leath, 4097. There are some rub marks on the plastic. The case has an unmarked lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&query=cylinder1168
- Unknown (Cylinder EDI 0058)
  This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type. The cylinder has split into two pieces inside the case and cannot be safely removed from the case. The case has no lid or bottom. No writing is printed on the rims of the cylinder so the title, performer and ID number are unknown. The cylinder is unplayable.
- "Swanee-One Step" (Cylinder EDI 0059)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Lenzberg's Riverside Orch., 4034. There are some rubbing marks on the plastic. The case has a lid with no label. The lid is in two pieces.
  This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be streamed here: http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&CISOPTR=511&CISOBOX=1&REC=1
- "Camp Songs, US Army - No.2" (Cylinder EDI 0060)
  This is an Edison cylinder sound recording case. No cylinder was found in the case. The performer and ID number are printed as, Chorus of Male Voices, 3403.
  This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be streamed here: http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&CISOPTR=686&CISOBOX=1&REC=13
- "I've Got the Blues for My Kentucky Home" (Cylinder EDI 0061)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Premier Quar., 4219. There are some rubbing marks on the plastic. The case lid is illegible.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder1233
- Unknown (Cylinder EDI 0062)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The cylinder has crumbled into pieces inside of the case. The performer, title, and ID number are not visible on any of the pieces. The case has no lid. The cylinder is unplayable.
- "Prophete" - Ah! Mon Fils. (Cylinder EDI 0063)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Marie Delna, 28126. Some of the top of the inner plaster core has chipped away. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and can be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder1233
- Song, "Old Folks at Home" (Cylinder EDI 0064)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The Id number is printed as 8781. There is no visible performer printed on the wax. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder7224
- Band, "Uncle Sammy March" (Cylinder EDI 0065)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The ID number is printed as 8632. There is no visible performer printed on the cylinder. There is a long vertical crack through the wax as well as a small gouge near the middle of the cylinder. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder4355
- "Old Folks at Home With Variations" (Piano) (Cylinder EDI 0066)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Benoist, 1908. There is some moderate mold damage and cracks to the inner plaster core on the bottom. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder811
- "Rock Me in My Swanee Cradle" (Cylinder EDI 0067)
  This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type. The cylinder cannot be safely removed from the case for inspection. The performer and ID number are printed as V. Dalhart and Chorus, 4605. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&CISOPTR=991&CISOBOX=1&REC=7
- "The Song of Songs" (Cylinder EDI 0068)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Leola Lucey, 4670. The cylinder is dirty. The case has a lid with no label.
  This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&CISOPTR=681&CISOBOX=1&REC=9
- "Old Dog Tray" (Cylinder EDI 0069)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, W. Van Brunt and Chorus, 3486. There is some lightening of the plastic around the bottom lip. The cylinder is dirty. The cylinder is in its original case.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder5695
- "I'm Forever Blowing Bubbles"- Medley Waltz (Cylinder EDI 0070)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Tuxedo Dance Orch., 3841. There is some lightening of the plastic at the bottom lip. The cylinder is in its original case.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder5962
- Band, "My Old Kentucky Home" (Cylinder EDI 0071)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and most of the ID number are illegible. There is severe mold damage and discoloration to a large portion of the wax surface. There is also a large vertical crack through the wax as well as a piece missing from the top of the cylinder. The cylinder is in the wrong case. The lid reads, "What's the [?]i[?]se."
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder1615
- Unknown (Cylinder EDI 0072)
  This is a Grey Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are not visibly printed on the wax. Mold damage covers almost the entire surface of the cylinder. Tape has been applied to the bottom of the case to act as support for the cylinder inside. There is no lid.
- "Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming" (Cylinder EDI 0073)
  This is a Purple Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Anna Case & Criterion Quartet, 29022. There are some small scratches and rub marks to the plastic. The case has no lid. The cylinder is in its original case.
- Unknown (Cylinder EDI 0074)
  This is a Grey Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer, title, and ID number are not visibly printed on the wax. The surface of the wax is completely obscured by mold damage. The case has no lid or bottom. Tape has been placed on the bottom of the case to support the cylinder inside.
- Tenor, "For Sale, a Baby" (Cylinder EDI 0075)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The ID number is printed as, 8626. There is no visible performer printed on the wax. There is some moderate mold damage. The cylinder is severely dirty. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder2725
- "Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming" (Cylinder EDI 0076)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Quartette, 9994. There is paper stuffed inside of the cylinder. The case, lid, and cylinder are all in excellent condition.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder3412
- "Kentucky Dream" (Cylinder EDI 0077)
  This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Leola Lucey and C. Hart, 3804. There is some lightening at the top edge of the plastic. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder6993
- "Mandy and Her Man" (Cylinder EDI 0078)
  This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Ada Jones and Len Spencer, 9236. The cylinder is severely dirty with scratch and rub marks on the wax surface. The case has no lid.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder8002
- "Washington's Farewell Address" (Cylinder EDI 0079)
  Cylinder is an Edison Blue Amber Record, marked 1654. Performed by Harry E. Humphrey.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&query=cylinder0715
- "Battle Hymn of the Republic" (Cylinder Edi 0080)
  Cylinder is an Edison Amberol four minute record, labeled number 79. The recording is performed by Miss Stevenson, Mr. Stanley and Chorus.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder7867
- "Beautiful Ohio" (Cylinder Edi 0081)
  Cylinder is an Edison Special four minute Amberol Record. The case is for "Tramp! Tramp! Tramp!" but the cylinder is actually for the Metropolitan Quartet's performance of "Beautiful Ohio," numbered 3759.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder5909
- "Coast Guard's March" (Cylinder EDI 0082)
  Cylinder is in an unlabeled case for Gold Moulded Records. Cylinder is marked number 830.
- "The Rosary" (Cylinder EDI 0083)
  Cylinder is an Edison Blue Amberol record labeled 1525. The recording is by Elizabeth Spencer and the Knickerbocker Quarter.
  This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&num=1&start=1&query=cylinder628
- "Schubert's Serenade" (Cylinder EDI 0084)
  Cylinder is a Columbia Phonograph Co. Grand Record, Number 4188